# Savkin Nikita

# **Front-end Developer**

**%** +7(906)041-42-85

□ no.colour.you.like@gmail.com

im linkedin.com/in/nikitasavkin

#### Skills

#### Programming languages

JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML5, CSS (SASS, SCSS)

#### Libraries & Frameworks

React, Redux

#### Additional

Git, GitHub, Gulp, NPM, BEM, Responsive design, Debugging

## **Projects**

#### E-commerce store

Website for a store that sells plants.

React | Redux | Firebase

https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/plants-e-commerce

#### Cryptocurrency Tracker

Tracking cryptocurrency in real time.

JavaScript | API | Chart.js

https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/Crypto

#### Movies navigation

Navigation with popular movie lists.

JavaScript | API

https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/Movies

#### Launcher

Website about a rocket engine testing company.

HTML | CSS(SASS) | JS https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/Launcher

## Languages

Russian – Native English – Pre-intermediate

#### **SoftSkills**

Critical thinking

Adaptability and Flexibility

Teamwork

# 2

#### **Profile**

I'm a passionate and detail-oriented Front-End Developer. I use my knowledge to create user-friendly web applications for various tasks. I care a lot about the quality of the code and what I create. I have experience in creating responsive websites and web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. I can assure that I can be a useful member of the company.

# Y

# **Experience**

> Front-end Developer (Personal websites & web applications)

March 2020 - Present

- Developed and maintained code for client websites primarily using HTML, CSS (SASS) and JavaScript;
- Manually tested sites in various browsers and mobile devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness;
- Wrote modern, performant, maintainable code for websites and web applications.

**Achievements**: engineered and implemented five adaptive websites, five JavaScript applications and e-commerce project using React.

#### Assistant cameraman @ TV Centre

September 2019 - June 2021

- Assistance to the cameraman in video recording news stories, sound recording, lighting installation.

**Achievements**: video recording of news with the participation of the mayor of Moscow, video recording special reports.

# Store Manager @ GAP

September 2016 – September 2019

 Control of store activities, accountability, selection and training of employee, control and management of personnel, interaction with customers.

**Achievements**: recruited and trained 20 employees, increased customer loyalty after controversial situations.



#### **Education**

The Complete JavaScript Course (Jonas Schmedtmann),

Complete React Developer Course (Andrei Neagoie)

2020 - 2021 // Moscow

Direction: Front-End Development

Moscow State University of Mechanical Engineering

2012 - 2016 // Moscow

Degree: Bachelor's Degree in Management